Osman KOYUNCU

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

E-mail: osmannnkoyuncuuu@gmail.com Phone: +90 530 236 28 78

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/osman-koyuncu/ Address: Turkey

GitHub: https://github.com/osmankoyuncuu

SUMMARY

Having 3+ years experience in IT and 1+ years of experience in developing front-end and back-end website architecture and designing user interactions on web pages. Dynamic Full Stack Software Developer with both front end and back end programming languages skills, developing complex solutions, processing strong creative thinking skills, highly energetic and integrated with strong troubleshooting abilities. Working with APIs and technical documentation. Have the ability to create algorithms effectively and communicate appropriately with team members. Always eager to learn various technologies, tools and libraries. Especially interested in React.js, Next.js, Node.js and Django.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Upwork Aug 2022 - Present

Full Stack Developer (Freelance)

- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Developed interactive, responsive and scalable frontend using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React.
- Created data visualization tools and integrated designs.
- Increased speed of product lifecycle and 100% of the time delivered projects within deadline.
- Designed 5+ websites with HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Tailwind codes and Increased patient satisfaction scores by 30%.
- Applied state management throughout the projects using React States and Redux.
- Planned and developed RestfulAPIs web services to manipulate dynamic datasets using Python Django
 Framework and consumed APIs using async js structure.
- Developed backend applications with Node.js, Express.js, Django, Django Rest Framework, MongoDb and PostgreSql,
- Studied on Computational Thinking, Operating Systems, Version Control Systems(Git & Github),
 Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC),
- Used SCRUM & Agile methodologies and JIRA while working on individual & group projects.

Ministry of National Defence

Sep 2015 - March 2022

Project Manager

Worked the projects on were completed on time and completely.

- Worked Education in harmony with people from different and cultural levels.
- 500+ people were trained in line with their targets.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML | CSS3 | JavaScript | React.js | Next.js | TypeScript | jQuery | Redux | SASS | Bootstrap | Material-UI | Axios | Python | Node.js | Django | Firebase | MongoDb | PostgreSQL | MySQL |Git | GitHub | Linux | APIs | Agile | Scrum | Jira | SDLC | OOP | Docker

SOFT SKILLS

Analytical Thinking | Problem-Solving | Strong Communication | Project Management | Time Management | Adaptability | Collaboration & Teamwork | Creativity | Entrepreneurship | Business Discipline

PROJECTS

- Recipe App: (https://recipe-app-one-jet.vercel.app/) The purpose of this project is to use the https://developer.edamam.com/edamam-recipe-api API to enable the user to reach recipes for meals and meals. The user can see the detailed recipe of the food she chooses. Skills/Tools: React, Styled Components, React-router-dom, Axios.
- Firecontact App: (https://react-fire-contact.vercel.app/) In this project, it is aimed to create a contact list using firebase realtime- database. Adding, deleting and updating contacts can be done. Skills/Tools: Firebase realtime-database library, Tailwind UI and React-toastify.
- Blog App: (https://osman-blog-app.netlify.app/) In this project, the aim was to create blog posts using firebase realtime-database and display them on the dashboard. You can add, delete, update, favorite and comment on blog posts. In the project, firebase realtime-database library was used for storing data, material-ui library for styling, react-router library for page transitions, formic and yup libraries for form structure and validation, and react-toastify library for notifications. In addition, firebase was used for login and authorization processes. Skills/Tools: Firebase realtime-database, Material-UI, React-router-dom, Formika-Yup, React-toastify.
- Stock App: (https://stock-app-gules.vercel.app/) In this project, it is aimed to create a stock management panel. Users cab enter companies, products, brands and can control the amount of stock bought and sold from these products and see them graphically. Skills/Tools: React components, Redux/Toolkit, Material UI, Formik-Yup, Tremor, Axios, React-toastify.
- Last Fm: (https://last-fm-react.vercel.app/) In this project, Last.fm apiden lists artists and their albums. It lists the artists on the homepage with the infinete scrool method. Details of selected artists are shown on a separate page. Skills/Tools: React, React-router-dom, React Custom Hook, React-query, Redux/Toolkit, Tailwind UI.
- **TicTocToe:** (https://cool-selkie-b66e6c.netlify.app/) Tic-tac-toe is a paper-and-pencil game for two players who take turns marking the spaces in a 3-by-3 grid with X or O. The player who succeeds in placing 3 of their marks in a horizontal, vertical, or diagonal row is the winner. **Skills/Tools:** Next.js, Typescript, PureCss.
- **Notes:** (https://notes-wheat-one.vercel.app/) In this project, it is aimed for the user to keep and track their notes. It has the ability to create, edit and delete content and tags related to user notes. Can filter

the notes it has by title and tags. **Skills/Tools:** React, Typescript, React-router-dom, Bootstrap, React-select-multi.

- Blog App: In this project, it is aimed to create a more complex database structure. Users can create, update, delete, read like and leave a comment on blogs. Basic auth functionality can be used like login, change password, forget password. Also, users can only perform update functionality on their blogs. . Skills/Tools: Django Rest Framework, Python-decouple.
- Flight App: (https://osmankoyuncu.pythonanywhere.com/swagger/) In this project, it is aimed to create an application users can create, update, delete or read reservations. Nested serializers are used to create objects on two different tables at the same time. Also, we used class-based views and overridden some methods to create custom functionalities. Skills/Tools: Django Rest Framework, Swagger, Coverage-testing, Django debug toolbar, Python-decouple, DRF-Yasg.
- Personnel App: In this project, the personnel of each department should be listed. Adding, editing and deleting personnel can only be done by people with admin authority, user can only be viewed.
 Skills/Tools: Django Rest Framework, Dj-Rest-Auth, DRF-Yasg, Python-decouple.

EDUCATION

Anadolu Univesity Sep 2018 – Aug 2019

Justice, Associate's degree

University of National Defence Sep 2011 – Aug 2015

Electronic Engineering, Bachelor's Degree

CERTIFICATIONS

•	Docker - BTK Akademi	Jan 2023
•	Beginner Frontend Web Development Path - Patika.dev	Jan 2023
•	Frontend Developer Course Certificate - Clarusway	Dec 2022
•	React Course Certificate - Clarusway	Nov 2022
•	Javascript Certificate - Sololearn	Oct 2022

LANGUAGES

Turkish: Native

English: Intermediate